Vipul Patil

QA/Test Engineer, Automation QA/Test Engineer.

Email - vipulbalupatil@gmail.com

Mobile - 9011383566

Hi, I'm an Automation QA Engineer and Manual QA Engineer, for over a 4.5 + Years. Experienced in Automation, Manual), DataBase, Backend API, and Mobile testing (Android & iOS).

I have ability to manage multiple projects. **Excellent** interpersonal and **communication skill**, comfortable to work in multi time zone, multi-region and multi-cultural environment.

Work Experience – [5 + Years]

1 - Intertek India Pvt Ltd | Oct 2023 - June 2024

Designation - QA Engineer Project - EDC - [Electro] Domain - Healthcare

Technologies - Java, Cucumber, Selenium, Git, Jenkins, TestNG, Jira, Perfecto,

Gherkin, TypeScript and Playwright.

- Working as both as Automation and Manual Test Engineer on EDC project.
- Development of automation scripts using Cucumber Java Selenium BDD framework.
- Management of framework updates and created utilities.
- Execution and monitor tests on Perfecto.
- Conduction of Mix-panel testing and performed Accessibility testing using AXE Dev Tool and NVDA
- Responsible for Understand Project requirement and Data analysis, Test Cases Development,
 Automation and Execution.
- Data base testing using SQL.
- Automated browser-based application testing using TypeScript and Playwright.
- Validated RESTful APIs (POST, GET, PUT, DELETE) using Postman and Playwright.

2 - SGS India Pvt Ltd | Dec 2022 - Oct -2023

Designation - QA Analyst Project - Cambia

Domain - Healthcare domain.

Technologies - Java, Selenium, Git, Jenkins, TestNG, Jira.

- Owned both Manual and Automation testing activities for Cambia projects.
- Involved in Design and implementation of Automation testing framework using Java-selenium framework from scratch for both UI and API automation.
- Worked on end-to-end manual testing activities.
- Created test management, execution, and monitoring for **Web** platform.
- Conducted API testing using Postman.
- Built performance testing framework with AWS CloudWatch and JMeter to optimize scalability
 and resource utilization.
- Implemented data-driven testing with Playwright, using external datasets (JSON) to validate
 multiple test scenarios dynamically.

3 - GVS Cibatech PVT Ltd Mumbai. | July 2019 - Oct 2022

Designation - Analyst Project - Caresource

Domain - HealthCare domain

- Worked as **Manual and Automation testing** Engineer on the **Caresource** project.
- Artificial Intelligence (AI) Testing.
- Responsible for Understand Project requirement and Data analysis, Test Cases Development,
 Automation and Execution.
- Machine learning **Algorithm testing.**
- Perform Data Quality, Integration, Performance testing, Robustness, Interpretability Testing.
- Worked on end-to-end manual testing activities.
- Responsible for Understand Project requirement and Prepare Test Cases and Execution. Writing
 effective and optimized Test Cases in JIRA using BlackBox Testing techniques.
- Find bugs in the application and raise them on JIRA. Active participation in weekly/daily status
 calls with the client.
- Used API testing with Playwright to validate API responses directly within the same framework, minimizing the need for separate tools.

Automation Testing:

- Expertise in Automation framework Design and Development.
- Expertise in writing end-to-end scenario scripts in Java.
- Expertise in Cucumber framework, Java Hybrid and Robot framework.
- Strong knowledge on tools Selenium WebDriver, Postman, SOAPUI and Docker.
- Expertise in testing web services SOAP and REST API Testing.
- Expertise in Playwright and TypeScript for end-to-end test automation and API testing.
- Solid understating on software builds tools such and CI/CD with Jenkins
- Strong knowledge on Junit, TestNG and Extent Reports Data Driven Testing.
- Strong knowledge on AWS, google cloud.
- Strong knowledge on **Database Testing** with **SQL**.

Manual Testing:

- Strong knowledge on SDLC and STLC concepts.
- Strong knowledge on Smoke, Sanity, Functional and System testing and accessibility testing.
- Very good knowledge in Ad-hoc testing, Exploratory testing, Acceptance testing(UAT).
- Very good knowledge on Compatibility Testing and Globalisation testing.
- Strong knowledge in Test Plan, Test Analysis, and Impact analysis.
- Mobile Application Testing (Android, iOS).
- Strong knowledge on **Project management tool JIRA and Agile Methodology.**
- Prepared Weekly status Report and send to higher authority.
- Good experience in Software Testing and Quality Assurance in Healthcare Domain.

Programming Skills-

- Strong knowledge on Java, Python its libraries.
- Good knowledge of TypeScript for building scalable Playwright test scripts.
- Good knowledge on C and C++ and gherkin.
- Good Knowledge on Test Driven Development and Data driven Testing.
- Good understanding UI skills like Angular, CSS, HTML and React

Education Details-

- Completed Master of Science from Fergusson college Pune [Autonomous] Affiliated to Savitribai Phule Pune University 2017 to 2019.
- Completed Bachelor of Science in Shivraj college Gadhinglaj under Shivaji University Kolhapur 2014 to 2017.
- Completed 12th in Sambhajirao mane jr. college Gadhinglaj in 2014.
- Completed Schooling in Ghataprabha High School Salamwadi in 2012.